Press Shift A and go to Surface NURBS
Curve. If you go to Edit Mode, you see
that the NURBS Curve has what is called
a hull with vertices that you can
manipulate. Clicking on endpoint U will
make the curve endpoints the same as the
hull.
So now you can manipulate that curve in
Edit Mode. Just like with a mesh, you
can select two vertices and right click
then choose Subdivide to add another
vertex. You can select all and uh Shift
D to duplicate.
Then with everything selected, press F
to fill the NURBS surface.
Now you can manipulate the vertices to
create a perfectly smooth surface. This
is the basics of NURBS modeling. To add
an edge loop, you can't just press Ctrl
R. You will need to select all these
vertices and then right click and choose
Subdivide.
NURBS surfaces are great for modeling,
for example, the overall shape of a car.
Once the main shape is finished, you can
convert it to a mesh and then add more
detail with normal polygonal modeling.